Contactar

www.linkedin.com/in/aguilarmariana (LinkedIn)

Aptitudes principales

Gestión de proyectos Renewable Energy Entrepreneurship

Languages

Italiano (Limited Working)
Spanish (Native or Bilingual)
English (Native or Bilingual)
German (Limited Working)

Certifications

Expert in Photovoltaic Plant Design

Honors-Awards

Bec.Ar Scholar

Segunda Escolta de la bandera argentina

Academic Merit Award

Academic Merit Award

Outstanding Academic Achievement

Mariana Aguilar (mariaguilar.eth)

LAC Sales Manager @Intermepro Argentina

Extracto

I am an industrial engineer with B2B sales expertise across LATAM.

Extensive experience working with clients/partners, C-level executives and cross-functional teams in global settings.

Most of my career has been dedicated to Sustainability and Renewable Energy, earning experience that can be extrapolated to other industries. I have also developed operational skills in multiple family businesses.

I created a site to provide background information about who I am, so that you can learn more about me and my story: https://maguilarq.notion.site/

Experiencia

Intermepro S.A.

Sales Manager - Latin America and Caribbean octubre de 2017 - Present (4 años 6 meses)

Provincia de Córdoba, Argentina

We are a leading company that provides comprehensive sustainability solutions together with the world's leading brands. We develop and build projects that require end-to-end solutions and we support our network of distributors and partners in Latin America and the Caribbean.

Global Shaper Global Shaper julio de 2014 - Present (7 años 9 meses)

The Global Shapers Community is a network of Hubs developed and led by young people who are exceptional in their potential, their achievement and their drive to make a contribution to their communities.

Shapers are highly motivated individuals who have a great potential for future leadership roles in society. They are selected on the basis of their achievements, leadership potential, and commitment to make a difference. Through the Global Shapers Community, Shapers are provided with opportunities to connect with the worldwide network of Global Shapers, to network with other World Economic Forum communities, and to represent the voice of youth at World Economic Forum events. Shapers are united by a common desire to channel the members' tremendous energy and enthusiasm into building a more peaceful and inclusive world.

I was selected to participate representing the voice of youth in the following World Economic Forum's events:

- Latin America Annual Meeting World Economic Forum México 2015
- Annual Meeting of the New Champions Tianjin, China 2016
- Annual Meeting Davos, Suiza 2017

agener

CoFounder

marzo de 2018 - diciembre de 2021 (3 años 10 meses)

Argentina

Agener is a start-up that provides 4th Industrial Revolution energy solutions to SMEs in Argentina. We care about sustainability and the intersection with cutting edge technology.

World Energy Council

Future Energy Leader's Board Member marzo de 2018 - marzo de 2021 (3 años 1 mes)

As one of the 100 Future Energy Leaders of class 2017, I was selected by the World Energy Council to be a member of the Development Committee of the FEL100 Board.

The FEL-100 global impact community of exceptional young professionals share a commitment to:

- -address the urgent need to humanise energy
- -seek innovative solutions for more energy and climate neutrality in the context of affordability and equality
- -engage in national, regional, and global activities and events
- -deliver innovative projects in support of our global energy community

Gobierno de la Provincia de San Luis

Undersecretary of Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency diciembre de 2015 - agosto de 2017 (1 año 9 meses)

San Luis, Argentina

With a Peace Treaty between Economic Development and the Environment
- strategy 2020, the government of the Province of San Luis established
priorities and a strategy for introducing sustainability in all of its public policies.
The Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency Secretariat, as part of the
Ministry of the Environment, Agriculture and Industry, developed concrete
projects and public policies that included the construction of electricity
generation plants based on renewable energy sources (mainly solar, biomass,
hydroelectricity), as well as the distribution of small solar and wind energy
generators for rural populations without access to the grid, the creation of
awareness campaigns for the rational use of energy, among others.

Energía San Luis Renewable Energy Manager junio de 2014 - diciembre de 2015 (1 año 7 meses) San Luis, Argentina

Government owned company with the mission to manage and operate energy related facilities, projects and services.

Capdevila ite
Business Development
abril de 2013 - marzo de 2014 (1 año)
Stuttgart, Baden-Württemberg, Germany

capdevila ite © is a knowledge based company dedicated to analyse and optimize the performance of photovoltaic power generation projects. We apply software tools, including proprietary, and a system approach from development to performance verification phases of the project.

Our focus is to provide expert support to manufacturing, integrator & financial companies involved in the utility & commercial scale photovoltaic business.

Rubol

Final Project in Social Corporate Responsibility mayo de 2011 - junio de 2012 (1 año 2 meses) Córdoba, Argentina

Diagnosis of the SCR state of the company.

Activity planning based on the company's business strategy and its objectives. Elaboration of their first Sustainability Report under ISO 26000 and GRI guidelines.

CSR Performance Indicators

Drimcom Marketing Team Member agosto de 2011 - octubre de 2011 (3 meses) Córdoba, Argentina

Market study of educational applications for tablets. Creation of the marketing plan and market penetration strategies.

Educación

Ajou University

Specialization, Energy Technology · (agosto de 2014 - octubre de 2014)

Universidad Tecnológica Nacional

Ingeniería Industrial, Ingeniería Industrial, Ingeniería Industrial · (2006 - 2012)

World Energy Council - Argentine Committee

Training Program for Energy Leaders, Energy (2016 - 2016)